The rough road across the plain soon became so bad that we tried to get Bruce to drive back to the village we had come from.
Even though the road was littered with boulders and pitted with holes, Bruce was not in the least perturbed.
Glancing at his map, he informed us that the next village was a mere 20 miles away.
It was not that Bruce always underestimated difficulties. He simply had no sense of danger at all.
No matter what the conditions were, he believed that a car should be driven as fast as it could possibly go.
As we bumped over the dusty track, we swerved to avoid large boulders.
The wheels scooped up stones which hammered ominously under the car.
We felt sure that sooner or later a stone would rip a hole in our petrol tank or damage the engine.
Because of this, we kept looking back, wondering if we were leaving a trail of oil and petrol behind us.
What a relief it was when the boulders suddenly disappeared, giving way to a stretch of plain where the only obstacles were clumps of bushes.
But there was worse to come. Just ahead of us there was a huge fissure.
In response to renewed pleadings, Bruce stopped.
Though we all got out to examine the fissure, he remained in the car.
We informed him that the fissure extended for 50 yards and was two feet wide and four feet deep.
Even this had no effect.
Bruce went into a low gear and drove at a terrifying speed, keeping the front wheels astride the crack as he followed its zigzag course.
Before we had time to worry about what might happen, we were back on the plain again.
Bruce consulted the map once more and told us that the village was now only 15 miles away.
Our next obstacle was a shallow pool of water about half a mile across.
Bruce charged at it, but in the middle, the car came to a grinding halt.
A yellow light on the dashboard flashed angrily and Bruce cheerfully announced that there was no oil in the engine!